# DANIELE GATTI

# Lead UX Designer

Availability: Immediate

Location: Via Belgrado,21 Ladispoli (RM) Italy

# PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a Lead UX Designer and Researcher with 20 years of experience in both client-side and agency roles.

I also have a technical background, and I'm proficient with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript.

I have worked for brands like Facebook, Nokia, Ebay, BP, Canon, Royal Mail, King, Puma Energy, Barrick Gold, ANZ and Old Mutual.

# CONTACT

Tel: +39 3342359748

LinkedIn: danielegatti

Email:

daniele.gatti@gmail.com

Portfolio: view on Notion

# CURRENT ROLE

#### LEAD UX/UI - Advanced Infrastructure

APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

I am responsible for the full stack UX of LAEP+, the most important map-based Net Zero planning tool in the UK, commissioned by the largest Distribution Network Operators in the country and used by local authorities, consultants and noprofit organisations to plan for a transition to green energy in local areas.

My main responsibilities include:

- UX strategy and roadmap, based on business objectives, user research, Web Analytics data and UX best practice;
- IA/taxonomy, wireframes;
- Prototyping and user testing;
- User research;
- Managing a subordinate UX Designer:
- Creating, updating and maintaining the corporate Design System;
- Coordinating with the front-end team to ensure feasibility of my designs and their faithful implementation in the product.

# SKILLS

- UX Design
- Information Architecture
- Wireframing and prototyping
- User Research
- User Testing
- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript

# **EDUCATION**

BSC (Hns) Open Degree - Open

#### University

2014-2018

Including subjects such as User Experience Design, ICT, Web Technologies, Design Innovation and UX Design. Qualification awarded in December 2018, 2.2 grade.

## PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

## LEAD UX/UI - Zonal

JULY 2022 - FEBRUARY 2023

I introduced UX as a discipline into the leading hospitality software development company in the UK, delivering solutions for POS, bookings, stock management, inventory and ordering, kitchen management and more.

## Senior UX Designer and Researcher - MachineMax

OCTOBER 2021 - JULY 2022

I was responsible for the full UX stack of activities, liaising with customers and internal stakeholders and collaborating with Product Management to shape and drive the roadmap. The product I worked on is an equipment management platform that aggregates heavy machinery performance data from proprietary sensors, OEM APis and third party telematics and helps users track and optimise activity, fuel consumption and CO2 emissions.

## Senior UX Designer and Researcher - Capital Economics

SEPTEMBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2021

I was responsible for all UX research and design activities within the Product Management team, developing the content delivery system (a custom WordPress website) that is used by clients to access their subscription services (macroeconomic publications and data). I introduced UX as a discipline in the company (as previously all digital work was outsourced) and shared responsibilities for product management with the rest of my team.

## UX Designer and Researcher – Scalable Software

NOVEMBER 2017 – SEPTEMBER 2019

I was responsible for all User Experience research and design in a software development company, working on an IT Asset Management Web Application (Asset Vision). The main project I worked on is <a href="mailto:showcased">showcased in my portfolio</a>. I was part of the Operations team which mostly included software developers, but I also worked with Marketing, Solutions Consultants and the UAT team to both gather information from customers and drive UI enhancements to the product.

## **UX Designer and Researcher - Canon Europe**

AUGUST 2016 - NOVEMBER 2017

I was one of the two in-house UX Specialists in the Web Presence team, looking after the full UX stack of activities for all of Canon EMEA's 49 marketing websites. I was responsible for all the UX activities relating to the B2B business unit, and I was one of the key players in the full restructuring of the B2B area of the corporate website.

#### UX Designer and Researcher – MerchantCantos

**DECEMBER 2012 – JULY 2016** 

## UX Designer and Front End Developer – DST OUTPUT

JUNE – DECEMBER 2012

## UX Designer (contract) - BT

MARCH 2012